Find a fixed rate today and save yourself some money on your next energy deal

    Find a new deal in less than 30 seconds!

    Find a fixed rate today and save yourself some money on your next energy deal

    Find a new deal in less than 30 seconds!

Privacy Notice
==============

We are LOVE ENERGY SAVINGS.COM LIMITED.
---------------------------------------

We operate under different trading names, including LOVE ENERGY SAVINGS, BUSINESS ELECTRICITY PRICES, BUSINESSENERGY.COM, BRITISH BUSINESS ENERGY, POWER COMPARE, ENERGY HELPLINE, BUSINESS ENERGY UK AND LIVE ENERGY PRICES.

We are incorporated in England and Wales (our registered office address is 2 Springfield Court, Summerfield Road, Bolton, BL3 2NT (Company number: [06322305](https://find-and-update.company-information.service.gov.uk/company/06322305/))) ("we", "us", "our") and we are committed to protecting and respecting your privacy. We are registered with the Information Commissioner's Office ("ICO") with registration number Z3162259.

This notice sets out the basis on which any personal data we collect from you, or that you provide to us, will be processed by us.

Please read the following carefully to understand our views and practices regarding your personal data and how we will treat it. When you provide your personal data to us, you are deemed to have read this privacy notice and to have accepted the terms set out herein.

This privacy notice is provided in a layered format so you can click through to the specific areas set out below.

[4          What happens if you do not provide the personal data that we request?. 15](#_Toc514951780)

* Important information and who we are

Our full contact details are:

LOVE ENERGY SAVINGS.COM LIMITED  
2 Springfield Court  
Summerfield Road  
Bolton  
BL3 2NT

Alternatively you can email us at [\[email protected\]](https://www.energyhelpline.com/cdn-cgi/l/email-protection)

Questions, comments and requests regarding this privacy notice are welcomed by using the contact details above.

Please note that you have the right to make a complaint at any time to the ICO, the UK supervisory authority for data protection issues ([www.ico.org.uk](https://ico.org.uk/)). We would, however, appreciate the chance to deal with your concerns before you approach the ICO, so please contact us in the first instance.

* Changes to our privacy notice

We keep our privacy notice under regular review to ensure that it properly reflects our use of your personal data.  We may make periodic changes to our privacy notice in the future, please check this page for any updates on your next visit to our website. 

This privacy notice was last reviewed and updated on **15 October 2024.**

It is important that the personal information we hold about you is accurate and current. Please let us know if any personal information which we hold about you needs to be corrected or updated at any time.

* How we collect personal data

Personal data, or personal information, means any information about an individual from which that person can be identified. It does not include data where the identity has been removed (anonymous data).

We use different methods to collect personal data about you, and there are different ways that we might do so. This privacy notice tells you what to expect when we collect personal data about individuals in the following ways:

* [visitors to our website](#Visitors31);
* [anyone who interacts with us or contacts us through social media](#Visitors32);
* [anyone who contacts us, or when we contact you](#Visitors33);
* [anyone who uses our services](#Visitors34);
* [you when you are transferred by one of our third party partners to our website, or one of our third party partners provides us with your personal data](#Visitors35);
* from [third party marketing partners](#Visitors36); and
* [from other energy brokers, where we have taken over the management and renewal of your energy contract](#energybroker)

This privacy notice also explains the types of personal information we collect from you, and the lawful basis we rely on under data protection legislation to use your personal data. Under data protection legislation, we are only permitted to use your personal data if we have a lawful basis for doing so as set out in the data protection legislation. Where we rely on our legitimate interests (or those of a third party) as the lawful basis for processing, we have done so on the basis that our legitimate interests (or those of a third party) do not override your interests and fundamental rights. This is called the "balancing test".

Please note that you can access Home Energy price comparison services from our website. If you access Home Energy price comparison services, please note that you will be transferred to our partner, Decision Tech. This privacy notice does not apply to any personal data you submit to Decision Tech when using the Home Energy price comparison services. Please check Decision Tech’s privacy notice before you submit any personal data to their website.

* Visitors to our website
    * We develop our websites here in-house, at Love Energy Savings.Com Limited, so all personal data collected about your visit to our website is handled internally by our employees. You can rest assured that all our employees receive training on data security and that we take the protection of your personal data seriously.
    * We also partner with other utility companies from time to time to provide you with price comparison services. In this case, we operate the website and this privacy notice applies to any personal data we collect about you when providing this service.
    * End-User Analytics and Cookies

We will collect details of your visits to our websites, including traffic data, location data, weblogs and other communication data and the resources you access on our website. We also collect information about your device and your visits to and use of our site, including, where available, your device's IP address, geographical location, operating system, referral source, browser type, length of visit and number of page views. We will collect this information for the purposes of system administration, optimising the use of our site and reporting aggregate information to third party suppliers. This is statistical data about our users' browsing actions and patterns, and does not identify any individual.

In particular, we use an analytics service provider for website traffic analysis and reporting and to track information such as which browser, screen resolution and IP address you are using to access our website, in addition to tracking your movements around our website.  Please see section 3.4 for more details on how we use this information.

Please note that we do use cookies on our website. More information on how we use cookies can be found in our [Cookies Policy](https://www.energyhelpline.com/about-us/cookie-policy "Cookie Policy").

* Third parties

Our site contains links to and from the websites of our third party partner networks, suppliers and affiliates. If you follow a link to any of these websites, please note that these websites collect personal data for their own purposes and have their own privacy notices. We do not accept any responsibility or liability for these third parties or their data activities on such websites. Please check their privacy notices before you submit any personal data to these websites.

* Social media

Any information you provide to us via social media (including messaging, "liking" or "following" and other communications) is controlled by the relevant social media network.

Our website contains links to our social media pages. We currently use:

* X: (formerly known as Twitter). Its privacy notice can be located [here](https://x.com/en/privacy)
* Instagram: Its privacy notice can be located [here](https://privacycenter.instagram.com/policy/?entry_point=ig_help_center_data_policy_redirect)
* Facebook: Its privacy notice can be located [here](https://www.facebook.com/privacy/policy/?entry_point=data_policy_redirect&entry=0)
* Linkedin: Its privacy notice can be located [here](https://www.linkedin.com/legal/privacy-policy)
* YouTube: Its privacy notice can be located [here](https://www.youtube.com/intl/ALL_uk/howyoutubeworks/policies/community-guidelines/)

We recommend that you read their privacy notices and contact them directly if you have any concerns regarding their use of your personal data.

* Contacting us

Our website provides you with different ways to contact us. You may choose to call us, or submit a query to us or request a call-back from us. All communications are handled, reviewed and responded to internally by us, unless we tell you otherwise.

As part of communicating with us, you will submit personal data about yourself which includes your name, email address, telephone number and any other additional information you choose to provide to us. We will use your personal data for our legitimate interests (or those of a third party) where it is necessary for any of the following:

* to contact you when you submit a query or complaint to our website or request us to call you back;
* to administer caller information (so we know if you have called us before);
* to investigate and follow up with you in regard to any query or complaint you make to us (as applicable); and
* to deal with your query.

We will retain records of our correspondence with you, for a period of 7 years from the date of last correspondence.

Please note that we record all telephone calls from our call centre, either when we contact you or you contact us. We use a third party service provider to provide call recording and other telecommunication services on our behalf. It is in our legitimate interests to record these calls to:

* ensure we are providing you with excellent customer service;
* use for training purposes for our call centre staff; and
* assist us in the future, if we ever receive a complaint from you and to enable us to investigate your complaint.

We will retain copies of call recordings for a period of 7 years from the date of your call.

* Using our services

Our website provides price comparison services for energy suppliers. We will collect personal data from you when you complete a form on our website in order to access our price comparison services or when you contact us by post, telephone or email.

We also have partnerships with other companies, and therefore we (or they) are able to offer you price comparison services for water, telecoms, insurance, waste and other services. We explain in section 5 below what personal data and the circumstances where we will share your personal data with these companies.

The table below sets out the categories of personal data we collect from you, the purposes for which we use your personal data and the lawful basis we rely upon for processing your personal data:

| **Category of personal data** | **Purpose** | **Lawful basis of processing** |
| --- | --- | --- |
| ·        Title, first name, surname, email address, telephone number, mobile number, and address; and<br><br>·        Any other personal data you provide us with | To provide you with our price comparison services and our online account to manage your business utilities (Love Hub).<br><br>To send your details to our energy partner, for them to enter into a contract with you for provision of their services | It is in our legitimate interests to use this information to be able to deliver our service and to provide you with a realistic indication of prices available to you<br><br>Contractual necessity, as this information is needed by us to perform our obligations under the contract. |
| ·        Title, first name, surname, email address, telephone number, mobile number, and address; and<br><br>·        Any other personal data you provide us with | To contact you in relation to utility renewals | It is in our legitimate interests to use this information to deliver our service to you and ensure you are aware when your current utility contact expires |
| ·        Meter number, meter serial number and business address | To undertake the following searches with GB Group Services (and other similar third party data providers from time to time) (where applicable): (i) with your address to find a meter number associated with that address; (ii) with your meter number to check it is associated with the business address we hold; and (iii) using your meter serial number to confirm your meter number | It is in our legitimate interests to undertake these searches to ensure we have an accurate meter number for you in order to provide you with a realistic indication of prices available to you and to ensure it matches your business address |
| ·        Meter number, annual consumption and business address | To undertake searches with ElectraLink (electric) and GB Group (gas) to confirm your consumption (including half-hourly data where relevant), your current energy supplier and the business address associated with that meter, in order to provide a more realistic indication of prices available to you, for the purpose of locking-in and managing your contract effectively. | Consent (ElectraLink only)– you will be provided with a clear choice to participate in these searches and share your data with this third party and you have the right to withdraw consent at any time in accordance with section 9.3(f). Please also see section 5 for more information.<br><br>In relation to GB Group, it is in our legitimate interests to undertake these searches to ensure that: (a) the details you have provided us with are accurate; (b) we provide accurate information to your new energy provider to mitigate the risk of any errors and/or delay for you in signing-up to your new energy contract; and (c) to help us manage your contract effectively by assessing your usage throughout the term of the contract |
| ·        Title, first name, surname, email address, telephone number, mobile number, and address; and<br><br>·        Any other personal data you provide us with | To provide you with price comparison services on behalf of our water partner<br><br>To send your details to our water partner, for them to enter into a contract with you for provision of their services | It is in our legitimate interests to use this information to be able to deliver our service and to provide you with a realistic indication of prices available to you |
| ·        Title, first name, surname, email address, telephone number, mobile number, and address; and<br><br>·        Any other personal data you provide us with | To provide you with price comparison services on behalf of our telecoms partners<br><br>To send your details to our telecoms partners, for them to enter into a contract with you for provision of their services | It is in our legitimate interests to use this information to be able to deliver our service and to provide you with a realistic indication of prices available to you |
| ·        Title, first name, surname, email address, telephone number, mobile number, and address; and<br><br>·        Any other personal data you provide us with | To refer you to our insurance partner, waste or other service partners, for them to provide you with their price comparison services | Consent – you will be provided with a clear choice to share your data with these third parties and you have the right to withdraw consent at any time in accordance with section 9.3(f). Please also see section 5 for more information. |
| ·        Title, first name, surname, email address, telephone number, mobile number, and address; and<br><br>·        Any other personal data you provide us with | To carry out our obligations arising from any contracts entered into between you and us | Contractual necessity, as this information is needed by us to perform our obligations under the contract |
| ·        Title, first name, surname, email address, telephone number, mobile number, and address; and<br><br>·        Any other personal data you provide us with | To notify you about any changes to our services | Contractual necessity, as this information is needed by us to perform our obligations under the contract |
| ·        Title, first name, surname, email address, telephone number, mobile number, address and IP address; and<br><br>·        Any other personal data you provide us with | To ensure that content from our website is presented in the most effective manner for you and your device | It is in our legitimate interests to study how customers use our products/services, to develop them and to grow our business |
| ·        Title, first name, surname, email address, telephone number, mobile number, address and IP address; and<br><br>·        Any other personal data you provide us with | To enable us to effectively administer, develop, support and improve our website, improve your browsing experience by personalising our website and help us obtain and verify your contact details | It is in our legitimate interests to study how customers use our products/services, to develop them and to grow our business |
| ·        Title, first name, surname, email address, telephone number, mobile number, and address; and<br><br>·        Any other personal data you provide us with | To enable us to provide customer services in relation to our services and to deal with enquiries and complaints made by or in relation to our customers and/or products supplied to our customers | It is in our legitimate interests to provide you with our services, investigate and resolve your enquiry or complaint |
| ·        Title, first name, surname, email address, telephone number, mobile number, and address | To conduct feedback surveys | It is in our legitimate interests to use this information to be able to improve our service |
| ·        Title, first name, surname, email address, telephone number, mobile number, address and IP address; and<br><br>·        Any other personal data you provide us with | To allow you to participate in interactive features of our service, where you choose to do so | Consent – you will be provided with a clear choice to participate in these features and you will have the right to withdraw consent at any time in accordance with section 9.3(f) |
| ·        Title, first name, surname, email address, contact number, business postcode (if this is also your home address) | To pass your details onto a named third party for them to contact you about their services (for example, if you want to make an enquiry about boiler installation services). | Consent – you will be provided with a clear choice to consent to us sharing your personal data with our named third-party partner and you will have the right to withdraw consent at any time in accordance with section 9.3(f). |

We may also use your personal data for analytical purposes. Where this takes place, your personal data will be anonymised as far as we are able to do so for this purpose, and we rely on our legitimate interests to tailor our service, grow our business and to inform our marketing strategy.

In the course of using our services, whether you choose to switch utility suppliers or not, we will retain your personal data for a period of seven years from the date you provide us with your personal data and/or express an interest in our services, subscribe to our services, or re-subscribe to our services (whichever is the later).

* Our third party partners

We work with a number of third party partners to provide you with price comparison services. When you access our services through our third party partners, we will collect personal data about you in the following circumstances:

* When you are transferred to our website from one of our third party partner websites; and
* Where third parties provide us with your personal data. We rely on our third parties to notify you that they will be sharing your personal data with us.

Please note that we will be the controller of your personal data from the stage we are provided with your personal data (either directly from you or one of our third party partners, whichever is the earlier). You should refer to this privacy notice for details on how we will use and treat your personal data. Please refer to sections 3.1, 3.3 and 3.4 for further information on how we will use your personal data when we are providing you with our services.

* Our third party marketing partners

From time to time, we will obtain personal data from our third party marketing partners. This includes your name, email address, telephone number and business address. In these circumstances, we will take reasonable steps to ensure that such third party has collected your personal data fairly and lawfully and, if applicable, has obtained all appropriate consents required from you to allow us to market to you. We ensure that we use experienced business database providers and we take reasonable steps to ensure they take the protection of your personal data and compliance with data protection legislation seriously.

If we have obtained your personal data from a third party source, we will inform you of where we collected your personal data within a reasonable period of time of having obtained your personal data and provide you with a copy of this privacy notice.

We rely on our legitimate interests as a lawful basis for processing your personal data, to offer and promote our products and services to you.

* Subscribing to our marketing

If you are a customer, or have made an enquiry relating to our price comparison services (or services offered by one of our other trading names), you have an opportunity through the link in our Privacy Notice to object or opt-out of receiving marketing communications at the time of collecting your personal data.  If you have not opted out of receiving the marketing communication, we will contact you by email, SMS, telephone or via targeted social media adverts in our legitimate interests to promote our products and services that are relevant to your purchase or enquiry. We will also provide you with the option to unsubscribe or object to continuing receiving marketing with each communication. **You have the right to object to receiving these communications at any time by contacting us on the details above.**

If you are not a customer but are interested in our products and services or you are an existing customer but interested in other products and services we offer (excluding our energy products and services you have an opportunity through the link in our Privacy Notice to object or opt-out of receiving  marketing promotional material, updates, reminders and communications. If you have not opted out, we will collect your contact details (name, postal address and email address) to provide you with such communications.

You have the right to opt out at any time. For full details on how to opt out please see [above](#Section1).

We use a third party email and SMS marketing platform service provider, to manage our SMS and newsletter subscriptions. They will not use your personal data for any other purpose other than as we instruct them to.

If you ever decide you no longer wish to receive our marketing communications, you can opt out at any time by unsubscribing from the mailing list, using the link provided in the marketing communications email, or by using the contact details [above](#Section1). If you do unsubscribe, please note that we will still keep your email in a separate secure list so that we can make sure that you do not receive our marketing communications again in the future. 

* Third party energy brokers

If we take over the management of your contract from your existing energy broker, your energy broker will provide us with certain information about you. This will include your name, email address, contact number and meter number, which we will use for the purposes set out in section 3.4 above (including contacting you in relation to utility renewals).

Where we have received your personal data in these circumstances, we will provide you with a copy of this privacy notice either at the time of first communicating with you or at the latest, within one month of having received your personal data, and we will also inform you of who provided us with your personal data.

* What happens if you do not provide the personal data that we request?

We will need some of your personal data as a contractual necessity in order to provide you with our services or contact you and follow up with you in respect of any query or complaint you have submitted on our website. For example, we need to know your personal contact details in order to identify you and contact you.

Where information is needed for these purposes, if you do not provide it we will not be able to provide you with our services, or contact you and follow up with you in respect of the query or complaint you have submitted on our website. We explain this is the case at the point where we collect this information from you.

* Your data and third parties

We use third parties to provide services to us from time to time. We will share data with them where it is in our legitimate interests for our business administrative needs. A list of third parties that we use and how they process personal data is set out in the table below. Please note that these third parties are located within the UK or the European Economic Area, unless otherwise stated below.

| **Third party** | **What data?** | **Why do we share this data?** | **How long is this data kept by this third party?** |
| --- | --- | --- | --- |
| Energy suppliers (gas and electric) | Title, first name, surname, email address, home number, mobile number and address | We share this data for a number of reasons, including:<br><br>·       To enable you to switch energy suppliers<br><br>·       To whom disclosure is necessary to enable us and/or a supplier to determine if you are eligible to subscribe to our services and/or the supplier’s services; and<br><br>·       To whom disclosure is necessary to enable us to provide you with any service to which you have subscribed (including for the purposes of contract fulfilment, processing payments, credit referencing, designing, maintaining and administering the site). | These third parties will be acting as controllers of your personal data. You will be notified of which energy supplier your personal data has been provided to at the relevant time. Please refer to their own privacy notice for information about how your personal data is used and retention periods. If you wish to exercise your individual rights in relation to your energy provider, you will need to contact them directly. |
| Water partner and/or our telecoms partners | Title, first name, surname, email address, home number, mobile number and address | We share this data for a number of reasons, including:<br><br>·       To enable you to switch water and/or telecoms suppliers;<br><br>·       To whom disclosure is necessary to enable us and/or a supplier to determine if you are eligible to subscribe to our services and/or the supplier’s services; and<br><br>·       To whom disclosure is necessary to enable us to provide you with any service to which you have subscribed (including for the purposes of contract fulfilment, processing payments, credit referencing, designing, maintaining and administering the site). | These third parties will be acting as controllers of your personal data. You will be notified of which water supplier and/or telecoms supplier (as applicable) your personal data has been provided to at the relevant time. Please refer to their own privacy notice for information about how your personal data is used and retention periods. |
| Price comparison service providers for insurance, waste and other services | Title, first name, surname, email address, home number, mobile number and address | We share this data to enable these third parties to provide you with price comparison services. The type of price comparison services you receive will depend on the specific service request you make. | This third party will be acting as a controller of your personal data. We will not share your personal data with price comparison service providers unless you confirm to us you are happy for us to do so. Please refer to their own privacy notice for information about how your personal data is used and retention periods. |
| ElectraLink | Meter number | We share this data to enable ElectraLink to undertake searches to ascertain your current energy consumption and confirm your current energy supplier and the address associated with that meter. This enables us to provide a more realistic indication of the prices available to you, for the purpose of locking-in and managing your contract effectively. | This third party will be acting as a controller of your personal data. Please refer to their own privacy notice for information about how your personal data is used and retention periods. |
| Third party data providers such as GB Group Services | Meter number, meter serial number and business address | We share this data to enable these third parties to confirm your meter number, gas consumption and the business address associated with that meter number. This enables us to provide a more realistic indication of the prices available to you and to ensure it matches your business address. | This third party will be acting as a controller of your personal data. Please refer to their own privacy notice for information about how your personal data is used and retention periods. |
| Cloud hosting service providers | Title, first name, surname, email address, home number, mobile number, business postcode (if this is also your home address) and any other personal data you provide to us | Hosting of our servers and all of our customer data. | We are responsible for deleting your personal data from the servers of our cloud hosting service providers in accordance with sections 3.3 and 3.4 above. |
| Telecommunications provider | Title, first name, surname, email address, home number, mobile number, business postcode (if this is also your home address) and any other personal data you provide to us | To provide our main call system and to record our calls | 7 years for call recordings |
| Email and SMS platform providers | Title, first name, surname, email address, home number, mobile number, business postcode (if this is also your home address) | To enable us to send marketing and servicing messages. | Please see section 3.3 above regarding marketing messages and 3.4 for servicing messages. |
| Electronic waste recycling service providers | Title, first name, surname, email address, home number, mobile number, business postcode (if this is also your home address), IP address and any other personal data you provide to us | To dispose of our hardware where we longer use it | The hardware received by these providers are securely wiped of any personal data on receipt before the hardware is recycled. |
| Leads2Trade | Title, first name, surname, email address, contact number, business postcode (if this is also your home address) | To make your introduction to Leads2Trade, for them to contact you in relation to your enquiry for boiler installation services. | This third party will be acting as a controller of your personal data. Please refer to their privacy notice for information about how your personal data is used and retention periods. |
| Energy Ombudsman | Title, first name, surname, email address, contact number, business postcode, meter number/s and any other data relating to your complaint | For applicable energy microbusiness customers who escalate their unresolved complaint to the Ombudsman Services, we are obligated to provide the Energy Ombudsman with all data (and information) relating to the complaint, to allow the Energy Ombudsman to provide their decision. | This third party will be acting as a controller of your personal data. Please refer to their privacy notice for information about how your personal data is used and retention periods. |
| Lead Forensics | IP Address | To obtain the limited company email addresses of those who have visited our website, to enable us to contact them about our service. | For the period of time we work with this Partner. |
| Survey Monkey | Title, first name, surname, email address, | To help us obtain your feedback about our service, to enable us to improve going forward.<br><br>Survey Monkey may process your personal data outside the UK. For more information, including on how we safeguard your personal data when this occurs, see below: ‘Transferring your personal data abroad’. | For the period of time use their Platform. |
| Google, Facebook and other analytics software providers. | Name and email address | We may use other companies to provide analysis and improve our services. For example, enabling us to market to other customers who may be interested in our services, by creating ‘Lookalike Audiences’. Where possible, we will anonymise personal data shared with them. | For the period of time we work with this Partner. |

* Disclosure of your information

We will not usually disclose your personal data other than as already explained in sections 3 and 5 above. However, there may be circumstances where we need to share personal data other than as anticipated in sections 3 and 5 above. These include:

* where we are legally required to disclose the information. This includes sharing the personal data with tax authorities and law enforcement agencies for the purposes of the prevention and detection of crime;
* where we need to disclose the personal data for the purpose of or in connection with any legal proceedings, or for the purpose of obtaining legal advice, or the disclosure is otherwise necessary for the purposes of establishing, exercising or defending legal rights;
* disclosure is required to protect our interests, or someone else's interests (for example, to prevent fraud or credit risk reduction);
* disclosure is necessary to protect your vital interests (for example if you are unwell at our premises, we may need to seek medical assistance);
* it is to a third party for the purposes of providing administrative or processing services on our behalf. If such disclosure is required we will take steps to ensure that the third party protects the personal data in the same way that we do and notify you of any changes to this privacy notice; and
* to any prospective purchaser of our business assets or organisation.

* Keeping your personal information secure

We know that you provide your personal data in good faith and expect it to be looked after. This is why we take the security of your personal data seriously. This means that we have taken steps internally in order to ensure that our systems adequately protect your personal data. This includes:

* locating all personal data that we control on servers located in the United Kingdom and EEA;
* ensuring strict access controls to your personal data on a need to know basis and monitoring such access to customer personal data;
* encryption of the personal data on our website and all electronic transactions using SSL technology; and
* where we have given you (or where you have chosen) a password which enables you to access certain parts of our site, you are responsible for keeping this password confidential, together with any login details and/or user details. We ask you not to share your password, login or user details with anyone.

Unfortunately, the transmission of information via the internet is not completely secure. Although we will do our best to protect your personal data, we cannot guarantee the security of your data transmitted to our website and prior to us receiving it. Any transmission is at your own risk. Once we have received your information, we will use strict procedures and security features to try to prevent unauthorised access including those measures set out above.

* Transferring Your Personal Data Abroad

It is sometimes necessary for us to transfer your personal data to countries outside the UK and EEA. This may include countries which do not provide the same level of protection of personal data as the UK or EEA. We will transfer your personal data outside the UK and EEA only where:

* the UK government has decided the recipient country ensures an adequate level of protection of personal data (known as an adequacy decision); or
* there are appropriate safeguards in place (e.g., standard contractual data protection clauses published or approved by the relevant data protection regulator), together with enforceable rights and effective legal remedies for you; or
* a specific exception applies under data protection law.

You can contact us if you would like any other information about protection of personal data when it is transferred abroad.

* Automated Decisions

We use automated decision making when you complete a form on our website and submit it to access our price comparison services. This means we make decisions using the personal data you provide using only technology and none of our employees or any other individuals have been involved.  You will receive quotes from suppliers, and these quotes will vary in price depending on the information you provide us, including how much your utility bill is usually (whether paid on a monthly, quarterly or yearly basis) and where you are located in the UK.  For example, if you usually pay a significant utility bill each month, this indicates that you have a high utility usage and therefore the quotes returned from our suppliers are likely to be higher as compared to someone who has a low utility usage and month bill.  **You have a right to object to automated decision-making – please see section** **9.3(e)** **below.**

* Your rights

You have rights in respect of your personal data and this section explains a bit more about those rights that are applicable to how we use your personal data, and the circumstances in which you are able to exercise these rights. If you would like more information about any of your rights, please contact us on the details set out [above](#Section1).

* Accessing your personal data

We want you to fully understand and be comfortable with how we use your personal data. You can contact us at any time to ask whether we process any personal data about you. If we do hold or use your personal data in any way, you have the right to access that personal data. All we ask is that:

* you make your request to access in writing to the contact details [above](#Section1);
* you verify your identity; and
* you are fair and reasonable with how often you make this kind of request (please note if you are unreasonable in the number and frequency of requests you make, we may charge an administrative fee for processing any further requests. We will notify you of this prior to incurring such an administrative fee).

Please allow us up to one month from receipt of your request (or verification of your identity, whichever is the later) in order to provide you with our response.

* Requesting more information

We hope that you can understand that it is very difficult to cover all the possible ways in which we collect and use personal data. We have tried to be as clear and as open as we can and will continue to update this privacy notice as our use of personal data develops. However, if you have any questions regarding our use of your personal information, we will be happy to give you peace of mind by answering any questions or providing any additional information that we can. If you do have any specific questions, or need anything explaining, please get in touch on the contact details [above](#Section1).

* Additional rights

You also have some additional rights that you may exercise as set out here. We may publish a policy, from time to time, to explain how we will handle such requests and what you can expect from us when you make a request to exercise your rights. If we do publish any such policy, we will provide a link to it here. In each instance we may ask you to make your request in writing to the contact addresses [above](#Section1) and provide verification of your identity.

* You have the right to request that we rectify any inaccuracy about you that we may hold, in which case we may ask you to verify the corrected information (for example, we may ask for a recent utility bill for proof of change of address).
* You have the right to request that we erase your personal data. Please be aware that we can only comply with such a request if
* your personal data is no longer required for the purposes it was collected for (for example, we need your personal information to respond to a communication or query);
* the collection, storage or use of the personal information by us is prevented by law;
* your personal data is not required for the purposes of establishing, exercising or defending a legal claim such as in the conduct of legal proceedings.
* You have the right to request that we restrict or refrain from processing your personal data:
* for the time it takes us to verify the accuracy of your personal data where you have disputed its accuracy;
* where the collection, storage or use of the personal data by us is unlawful but you decide not to ask for erasure;
* where, we no longer need your personal data but you need them for the purposes of establishing, exercising or defending a legal claim;
* for the time it takes to determine whether we have an overriding legitimate ground to continue to process your personal data, where you have exercised your right to object to processing.
* You have the right to data portability in respect of information we have collected from you based on consent or for the reason of entering into a contract (contractual necessity). If you exercise this right, we will transfer a copy of the information that you have provided to us ­­­at your request.
* You have the right to object to our use of your personal data:
* where we are using that information based on our legitimate interests, and where we do not have compelling overriding grounds to continue to use your personal data;
* at any time, where we use your personal data to send you the newsletter or any other type of direct marketing, in which case it will no longer be used for that purpose, but we may use it for another lawful purpose; or
* **where we have made a decision about you using automated decision making. Don't worry if you do not want us to use our automated system to process your personal data you can object to us using automated processing as we have another process in place where you can access our price comparison services by speaking to one of our advisors and contacting us at our call centre on the following number: 0800 1422 452.**
* You have the right to withdraw your consent at any time where we have collected your personal data based on your consent. Please note that this will not affect the lawfulness of any processing based on your consent prior to you making such withdrawal.

Copyright © 2024, energyhelpline. All rights reserved
